CHRISTIAN RAMÍREZ

+57 312 493 1789



ccramirez825@gmail.com



Pasadena, Bogotá, Colombia



Biologist - MSc Bioengineering

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/ccramirezm

PROFILE

Professional in biology with a master's degree in bioengineering, specialized in biomechanics and data analysis. Experienced in spider silk research, sports biomechanics and database use. Proficient in the use of computational tools, artificial intelligence and motion capture. Knowledge in programming and Microsoft 365 tools, allowing to tackle complex problems and optimize research processes at academic and business level. Experience as an IB teacher and private tutor in disciplines such as chemistry, mathematics, physics and biology, teaching in Spanish and English. Distinguished by assertive communication, group management and teamwork skills. Interested in working in the areas of information technology and security in the service of companies.

EDUCATION



🕮 Pontificia Universidad Javeriana

Master in Bioengineering - Cum Laude Degree and Recognition of Academic Excellence. 2021 - 2023



Pontificia Universidad Javeriana

Biology Undergraduate Degree - Recognition of Academic Excellence and Top SaberPro Scores in Colombia

2015 - 2019

SKILLS

- VICON Nexus (Motion Capture)
- Microsoft Excel
- Google Workspace
- Python and Javascript
- · Excellent assertive communication and adaptability
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Detail oriented and able to manage multiple tasks simultaneously
- Focused on finding effective solutions to personal and clients' problems

CERTIFICATIONS

- 2024 | CS50 Introduction to Programming. Harvard
- 2023 | Certificate in Key Concepts for Building a Sustainable Business Model.
- 2021 | Certificates in Project Based Learning, Environmental Education and Virtual Teaching. Politécnico de Colombia
- 2019 | Programming for Everybody Diploma. University of Michigan, Coursera.
- 2011 | Leadership Process. LVC

WORK EXPERIENCE

*IB Biology Teacher

Gimnasio Los Portales | August 2024 - Present

- Biology teacher for the IB high school area in English.
- Planning and development of classes for MYP and DP.
- Conducting internal assessments and thesis.
- Group management.

Private Tutor

Freelance | May 2019 - Present

- Preparation for specific tests: IB, SAT, ICFES (Saber).
- Tutoring for college and university in chemistry, physics, mathematics and biology.
- Development of classes in Spanish and English.
- · Provided support in homework and study techniques, enhancing students' academic performance and study skills.

Artificial Intelligence Trainer

Outlier | May 2024 - Present

- Large language model (LLM) training for the LATAM region.
- Writing text for model training.
- Evaluation of search results in AI models.

ASSET Tutor

ASSET Tutores | August 2017 - May 2019

- Tutor for high school students in various subjects.
- Preparation for ICFES (Saber) and IB tests.

LANGUAGES

- English C2 (EF SET Certificate 81/100 Proficient)
- · Spanish Native
- French A1